If Crusch-sama's goal should be attained,
（ラッセル･フェロー）
このたびの クルシュ様の狙いが
なるのであれば―
I'm sure it would suit your
desires, Wilhelm-dono.
ヴィルヘルム殿にとっても
悲願となりましょう
I expect the best.
期待しておりますよ
My, how unusual it is to see you!
これはこれは 珍しい方にも
お目にかかれましたね
これは失礼いたしました
My apologies.
I am the treasurer of the capital's merchant guild.
私は 王都の商業組合で
会計係をしております―
ラッセル･フェローと申します
以後 お見知りおきを
My name is Russell Fellow.
It's a pleasure to meet you,
Natsuki Subaru-dono.
ナツキ･スバル殿
Wilhelm-san, who was that?
（ナツキ･スバル）
ヴィルヘルムさん
今のは？
Russell Fellow.
（ヴィルヘルム･
ヴァン･アストレア）
ラッセル･フェロー
Despite what he said,
ああ おっしゃって
いましたが―
王都での財貨の―
he is shrewd, dealing in all of the capital's
internal and external financial matters.
表と裏の動きに
携わる辣腕(らつわん)です
Now, I was just about to head back inside.
さて―
そろそろ 中に
戻ろうかと思いますが
Do you have something to say?
何かお話があるのでは？
People calling themselves the Witch Cult plan
to attack Roswaal's domain in three days.
（スバル）
３日後 魔女教って連中が―
ロズワールの領地の襲撃を
企(たくら)んでる
I'd like to ask for your help in stopping them.
それをたたき潰すために
クルシュさんの力が借りたい
I see.
（クルシュ･カルステン）
なるほど やはり
動き出してきたようだな
So they have made their move.
It seems so.
（フェリックス･アーガイル）
ですね　まあ
ハーフエルフのエミリア様が―
Of course, from the moment that Emilia-sama,
a half-elf, entered the scene,
表舞台に立った時点で―
we foresaw something like this happening.
その辺のところは
予想されてたとおりですけど
I understand the situation.
（クルシュ）事情は把握した
My next question is why you chose
to come to me for assistance.
次は 協力者に
当家を選ぶ理由だが
Because, to be honest, you seem
the most likely to help right now.
（スバル）
ぶっちゃけ 今の状況で
１番可能性が高いはずだからだ
You've helped Rem and me—
俺とレムが こうして
世話になってるってのも…
Don't misunderstand.
（クルシュ）誤解するな
I helped you two because I was contracted to do so.
卿(けい)らの扱いに対しては
約定があるからだ
If you wish to negotiate,
you need to show me what I stand to gain.
交渉であるならば
こちらにどんな利益があるのか―
Otherwise, there is nothing to negotiate.
それを示さなければ
交渉とは言えん
If, with our assistance,
卿らは 当家の力を借りることで
魔女教という脅威を排除できる
you can eliminate the threat
posed by the Witch Cult,
what benefit would that be to us?
ならば 当家はどうだ
それを聞かせてもらおう
Tell me that.
If you help me out with this problem,
（スバル）
例えば 今回の窮地に
手を借してもらえることで―
I'll owe a huge debt to your camp.
そっちの陣営は
こっちに大きな貸しが作れる
Should I accept the proposal,
その提案を受け入れる場合―
it would mean Emilia's withdrawal
from the royal selection.
それは エミリアの王選からの
脱落を意味するが―
You understand that?
それが分かっての発言か？
What did you expect?
当然だろ
Placing your own domain's survival
in the hands of another lord
自分の領地の危機を
よその領主に丸投げするなど―
calls into question your ability to rule the nation.
王たる器 以前の問題だ
With that in mind, I prompt you again...
そのうえで 再度問おう
If you incur a debt to me through this deal,
今回の件で
貸しを作るのであれば―
it will mean the elimination
of Emilia's camp from the race.
それは エミリアの陣営の
敗退を意味する
Do you still wish for my help?
それで本当にいいのか
Even still...
それでも―
I want your help.
手を貸してほしい
If she dies, everything ends, anyway.
死んじまったら
何もかもおしまいなんだから
Understood.
分かった
In that case, the Karsten family
will render no assistance whatsoever.
それならば カルステン家は
一切の戦力を卿には貸し出さない
Huh?
First of all, the condition of Emilia's withdrawal,
まず１つ 卿がこちらに提示した
利点であり―
which you offered in desperation
as an advantage to me...
苦渋の末に飲み込んだ
エミリアの王選脱落だが―
It carries no weight in this negotiation.
これは この交渉において
手札にならない
But why?
（スバル）何でだよ
Isn't removing one of your rivals
enough compensation!?
ライバルが減るのは
そっちにとっても十分な見返りで…
Are you intentionally overlooking this?
言っていて気づかないのか？
Emilia's elimination from the royal selection
will happen with or without my involvement.
エミリアの脱落に関して言えば―
私の関与に関わらず
発生する事柄であるのだと
Then you'll let the Witch Cult slaughter
（スバル）
じゃあ 魔女教に襲われる
ロズワールの―
all of those villagers in Roswaal's domain!?
領地のあの村の連中は
見殺しにすんのか！
Do not change the subject, Natsuki Subaru.
話題をすりかえるな
ナツキ･スバル
It is Emilia who lacks the power
to protect that domain.
領地を守る力がないのは
エミリアであり―
And Emilia whose people will die
for her incompetence.
無能さで民草を失うのも
エミリアだ
It is none of my concern.
断じて 私ではない
B-But isn't standing by and letting
people die just plain wrong?
（スバル）
けど 知ってて見捨てるってのは
悪じゃねえのか
If you have the power to save them,
why wouldn't you!?
力があんなら 助けられるなら
どうして助けない！
Hey, I've heard enough—
ちょっと 黙って聞いて…
It's fine.
Allow me to correct one idea you have.
ひとつ 卿の考えを正そう
Say the Witch Cult does make a move.
魔女教が動くことはあり得よう
その推測は成り立つ
That what you say comes to pass.
However, the problem lies beyond that.
だが 問題はその先だ
Beyond that?
（スバル）その先？
It's actually very simple.
簡単な話だ
How do you know when and
where they will attack next?
なぜ 奴らが次に狙う場所と日時を
卿に特定できる？
（スバル）そ… それは…
W-Well...
卿もまた 魔女教であるなら
知り得て当然だが
If you had ties to the Witch Cult,
it would only make sense.
That's bull—
ふざけ…
Crusch-sama, please do not make jokes.
（レム）
クルシュ様
お戯れはよしてください
Subaru-kun has no ties to the Witch Cult.
I say that with the—
スバルくんが魔女教だなんて
そんなはずがないじゃ…
Really?
そうかな
Given what he says, if he cannot explain
how he knows these details,
ナツキ･スバルの発言を顧みて―
知り得た理由が口にできないなら
そう断言するほかにない
I can draw no other conclusion.
Have you never sensed any
such inclination in him?
卿は そういった心当たりを
感じたことはないのか
Not even once.
ありません
Regardless, as the matter calls his credibility
into question, I cannot lend assistance to Emilia—
いずれにせよ それらの理由が
信ぴょう性を欠くため―
当家がエミリアに
手を貸すことはでき…
The Witch Cult is coming, goddamn it!
魔女教徒は来るんだよ！
They'll slaughter the entire village,
leaving not a single survivor.
あいつらが 村の人たちを
皆殺しにするんだ
Just kill them.
殺す　殺せばいいんだ
They don't deserve to live!
All we have to do is butcher every single last bastard in that damn cult!
魔女教の奴らなんか―
あいつらなんか みんな
ぶっ殺しちまえばいいんだ！
That will solve everything! It's that easy!
そうすれば 全部全部
丸く収まるんだよ！
You get that, right?
分かるだろ
We can't let those bastards crawl the earth!
あいつらなんか
生かしておいたらいけねえんだ！
I'm gonna kill them!
奴らを殺す！
Please help me!
力を貸してくれよ！
Is this why you behave as you do?
卿の行いの源泉はそれか
魔女教憎し
Your hatred for the Witch Cult...
Is that your real reason for approaching Emilia?
それが 卿がエミリアに近づいた
本当の理由なのか
No, I—
違う！ 俺は…
What else but murderous intent could
one call that glint in your eye?
（クルシュ）
今 卿の瞳に宿る光を―
殺意であると
呼ばずして何とする
You're suggesting I'm using Emilia as
a pretense for revenge against them!?
俺が エミリアをダシにして―
奴らに復讐(しゅう)しようと
してるってのか！
My hatred has nothing to do with how evil they are!
俺の憎しみと
奴らの邪悪さは関係ない！
They can't be allowed to live...
あいつらは
生きてたらダメなんだよ
That's why we have to kill every one of them!
だから 皆殺しにするべきなんだ！
それで みんな助かるんだ！！
That will save everyone!
I am certain I have told you, Natsuki Subaru.
言ったはずだぞ ナツキ･スバル
自分すらだませないウソでは
他者は欺けない
That if your own lie doesn't fool you,
it will not deceive others.
Why...
どうして…
You don't know why?
（クルシュ）
分からないのか？ 卿は１度も―
You haven't once said
that you want to save Emilia.
エミリアを助けたいと
口にしていない
I cannot allow you to come any closer.
それ以上は 前に進むことは
許されませんな
（レム）スバルくん
Subaru-kun,
please calm down.
落ち着いて下さい
I can generally tell when the person
with whom I speak is lying.
私には 相対している人間が
ウソをついているかどうか―
おおよそ 見抜くことができる
昔から 交渉事で―
I am quite proud of the fact that I have
never been deceived in negotiations.
他者に欺かれる
経験がないことが自慢でな
Speaking from those years of experience,
その経験をふまえて
言わせてもらえば―
I can say you are not lying.
卿はウソを言ってはいない
W-Well, then...
なら…
You adamantly believe that your rant is true.
妄言を真実だと
かたくなに信じ込んでいる
That is nothing short of madness,
それは もはや狂気の沙汰
狂人というものだよ
Natsuki Subaru.
ナツキ･スバル
Ferris, heal his lip.
フェリス 治してやるといい
Don't bother!
（スバル）いらねえよ
Rem, let's go.
レム 行くぞ
Do you have anywhere else to turn?
（クルシュ）
ほかに当てはあるのか？
I hope you become a great ruler.
（スバル）
せいぜい いい王様になれよ
弱者を切り捨てる独裁者的な
The kind of dictator who abandons the weak.
In my master's stead, I thank you
（レム）
お世話になりました
当家の主(あるじ)に代わり
お礼を申し上げます
for the care you have given us.
What will we do?
どうしますか？
If what you say is true, we have little time.
スバルくんのお話が本当なら
猶予もありません
"If" it's true?
本当なら？
We have little time.
猶予もありません
Shall we return to Roswaal-sama's mansion?
ロズワール様のお屋敷に
戻りますか？
No, there's not much the two of us could do by going back now.
いや 今 俺らだけで戻っても
たいしたことはできない
There aren't enough of us.
戦力が足りないんだ
What the hell is Roswaal doing?
ロズワールは何してやがんだよ
ロズワール様は―
Roswaal-sama has been required to visit some officials within the domain.
領内の関係者の所を
訪問することになっていて―
He will stay with them for a few days.
数日は逗(とう)留している予定で…
That's why he can't do anything about the attack?
それが襲撃に対処できない
原因なのか
Then, unless we find reinforcements,
we won't get anywhere.
やっぱり 援軍を連れて戻らなきゃ
どうにもならねえな
What about Reinhard?
ラインハルトなら
力を貸してくれるんじゃねえのか
Wouldn't he help us?
Yesterday, he said that he would be
昨日 ご挨拶の折りに―
away from the capital for a while on a courtesy call.
王都には しばらくご不在だと
おっしゃっていました
Damn it!
（スバル）クソッ！
Why is everyone so damn useless!?
どいつもこいつも使えねえ！
Tomorrow, we'll have to look
for someone else to help us.
明日 ほかの協力者を探すしかない
You head to the knights' station.
レムは 騎士団詰め所に行ってくれ
I'm going to talk to one of the other candidates.
俺は あと１人の候補者に
あたってみる
Very well.
（レム）はい
The Witch Cult?
（プリシラ･バーリエル）魔女教か
Yes.
（スバル）
そうだ 放置しておけば
たくさんの人たちを傷つける
If left alone, they'll hurt lots of people.
Emilia won't be their only victim.
被害はエミリアだけじゃ
とどまらない
I want to defeat them before that happens!
そうなる前に奴らを倒したい
That's why I—
そのために…
（プリシラ）ウフフフフ
アハハハハ 面白い
面白いな貴様
Amusing... You are amusing!
Indeed.
なるほど
Any jester who makes it this far has mastered his act.
道化もここまでくれば
芸として極まったものじゃな
Wh-What's so funny about this?
う… 何が面白いんだ
I can appreciate your desperation,
なりふり構わずは結構
じゃが 考えが足りなすぎる
but you haven't thought things through.
In trying to aid your ally, you corner them,
benefit the enemy, and lose all control.
助けようとして―
味方を窮地に追いやり
敵に利する
始末に負えん　死んだほうが
死んだほうがいくらかマシじゃ
You're better off dying.
In fact, I could just lop off
your head for you right now.
いっそ 妾(わらわ)がそっ首を―
たたき落としてやってもよいぞ
Still, even in the face of such harsh treatment,
が こうまで手ひどい扱いを
受けながらも―
主を思って行動する
貴様の忠義だけは見上げたものじゃ
the devotion you show for your master
is commendable, if nothing else.
So...
そこで―
I will give you an opportunity.
機会を与える
A-An opportunity?
き… 機会？
Yes, an opportunity.
（プリシラ）
そう 機会じゃ
チャンスというやつじゃな
What you would call a "chance."
Lick it.
なめろ
（スバル）え？
Huh?
Crawl on the floor,
（プリシラ）
床にはいつくばり
羞恥と屈辱をかみしめて―
savoring the shame and humiliation.
And like a wretched beast,
無様(ぶざま)な野獣のように―
like a baby suckling on its mother's teat,
母の乳をしゃぶる赤子のように
妾の足をなめろ
lick my foot.
If you can do that, I'll consider your proposal.
それができれば
貴様の提案を考えてやる
If you don't want to, that's fine...
イヤならいいんじゃぞ
己のちっぽけな矜持(きょうじ)を優先し―
If you'd rather favor your minuscule pride
and abandon the mistress you wagged
your tail for to the wasteland, fine.
しっぽを振った主人を―
荒野へ見捨てるというなら
それもよい
どちらであれ
妾にとっては一興よ
Either choice you make will entertain me.
F-Fine.
わ… 分かった
It seems you really are just an insignificant man!
本当に貴様 つまらん男でしか
ないようじゃな
What you just displayed was
neither loyalty nor devotion.
貴様のそれは
忠義でも忠誠心でもない
It's something more filthy,
like a dog's dependence or a pig's greed,
もっと薄汚い犬のような依存と
豚のような欲望じゃ
you lazy pig who knows only desire!
欲しがるだけの怠惰な豚め！
A pig's greed is the ugliest thing there is!
豚の欲望が最も醜い
Even if the Witch Cult is defeated,
仮に 魔女教を退けたとしても―
I will strike down any camp you are part of!
貴様のような畜生を要する陣営など
妾が打ち滅ぼしてやる！
Your careless behavior and attitude
have led me to that decision!
貴様の軽率な行いと態度が
妾にそう決意させた！
アルデバラン
Aldebaran.
Hey, now... What happened in here?
（アルデバラン）
おいおい これはどうしたってんで
Throw that detestable fool out of here.
その不愉快な愚物を放り出せ
なんなら 切り捨ててもかまわん
Or kill him if you want. It matters not.
I think that matters quite a bit.
（アルデバラン）
そら構うだろ いろいろと
Let's go, brother.
ほら 行くぜ兄弟
Don't get so mad, Princess.
そう怒んなよ 姫さん
That fierce look will make
your cute face drop in value.
かわいい顔が 凶暴さで
価値を落とすぜ？
Unless you want your ruined face further ruined,
貴様の崩壊顔を
より破壊してほしくないなら―
take him away at once, Aldebaran.
とっとと連れていけ
アルデバラン
I've told you not to call me that...
（アルデバラン）
その名前で呼ぶなっつの
Can you stand, brother?
立てるか？ 兄弟
Yeah.
You seem okay.
（アルデバラン）大丈夫そうだな
I don't know what you were discussing,
何の話してたんだか
知らねえけど―
あの様子じゃ
うまくいかなかったみてえだし
but it looks like it didn't go very well.
If I take too long,
戻るのが遅(おせ)えと
姫さんが本気で―
she might seriously tell me to chop
you in half, so I'm heading back.
兄弟をぶった斬れとか
言い出しかねねえから 戻るぜ
Later, brother.
じゃあな 兄弟
That damn stuck-up bitch...
（スバル）あのクソ傲慢女が
She's forgetting that I saved her when we first met!
初めて会った時 助けてやった
恩も忘れやがって
Switch gears, Subaru.
切り替えろ
This is no time for those idiots to bog me down.
（スバル）
あんなバカどもに
引っかかってる場合じゃねえ
Sniff, sniff. Sniff, sniff.
That looks super painful! Are you okee?
お兄さん すごい痛そう
だいじょうび？
Huh?
You smell like blood, and not just from your lip.
（ミミ）
お兄さん 口だけじゃなくて
血のにおいするよ
Was your nose bleedy?
鼻血ダバダバ出た？
Now, Mimi, no getting into mischief.
（アナスタシア･ホーシン）
こーらミミ
おいたしたらあかんよ
'Kay!
（ミミ）あーい
I'm awful sorry she's been botherin' you.
（アナスタシア）
えらい すみません
うちの子がご迷惑かけて
確か… そう ナツキくんや
Aren't you...
Right, you're Natsuki-kun.
エミリアの騎士
ナツキ･スバルくん
Emilia's knight, Natsuki Subaru-kun.
Ain't this a coincidence?
これは奇遇やないの
Anastasia Hoshin...
（スバル）
アナスタシア･ホーシン
Anastasia Hoshin...
Chow time!
（ミミ）
いっただっきまーす
So, about the dragon carriage...
（スバル）
それで 竜車のことだけど
You don't beat around the bush.
さっそく本題に入ろうとする
You won't make anyone happy
by prioritizin' your own goals.
自分の目的ばっかり優先やと
相手は喜ばんよ
Trying to get on your partner's good side
is the basic rule of negotiation.
交渉の基本は
どんだけ相手の懐に入れるか
That's where you're lackin', Natsuki-kun.
ナツキくんは そこがアカンね
Sorry, but I've got a real problem on my hands.
悪いけど本当に困ってるんだよ
I want to leave the capital tomorrow, so...
明日には王都から出発したい
だから…
When you're up against my kind,
情に訴えかけるんも―
tryin' to appeal to sentimentality
is the worst strategy there is.
うちみたいな人種が相手やと
下策中の下策やね
But I applaud your effort.
でも 頑張りは認めよか
It's no easy task findin' a dragon carriage in the capital right now.
確かに 今―
王都で竜車確保するんは
だいぶ骨やしね
Apparently, someone's buyin' up all of 'em.
どこぞの誰かが買い集めたとかで
Here. The place at this address
should have a carriage left.
ほら ここに竜車が
残ってるはずのお店の場所と―
I've signed it with my own name.
うちの名前で
サインしといたわ
This'll square everything away.
これで都合つけられる
Don't put on airs...
もったいぶるなよ
I surely will put on airs.
もったいぶるよ
It's no fun if I just hand it to ya normally, right?
やって タダで渡したら
面白くないやろ？
I just wanted to chat with ya about this an' that.
うちはただ 世間話に
つきあってほしいだけ
Why bother with that?
You don't gain anything from it.
何でそこまで…
得るものなんてないだろ
I believe there's nothin' in this
world that has no meaning.
何の意味もないことなんて―
この世のどっこにもないと
うちは思うとるよ
You never know who might give ya some inspiration.
どこの誰から どんな着想が
得られるかなんて分からんもん
What do we talk about?
何を話したらいいんだ？
Hey, my lady,
（ミミ）
ねえねえ お嬢お嬢―
I wanna eat some more!
ミミ もっと食べたい
頼んでいーい？
Can I order?
（アナスタシア）
ええよ 好きなだけ食べ
Sure. Eat all ya like.
Oh, but don't get your mouth all messy with sauce.
あっ でも おソースで
お口汚すんはダメ
Wipe my face, please!
くしゅくしゅ拭いてー
Yay! I'll be back!
やったー！ 行ってくる！
Despite her looks,
（アナスタシア）
ああ見えても あの子
うちの私兵団の２番手なんやから
she's second-in-command in my private army.
Private army?
私兵団？
Um, um, I want this, too! And also, um, um...
It's quite famous in Kararagi.
（アナスタシア）
カララギやと有名なんやけどね
The Hoshin Company's personal
mercenary squad, Iron Fang.
うちのホーシン商会の
専属の傭(よう)兵団 鉄の牙
Ain't she super cute?
めちゃめちゃかわいいんや
抱いて寝ると もうたまらへんよ
Nothing beats sleepin' with her in your arms!
Lately, lots of people have been
gatherin' in the capital.
この王都も 最近いろんな人が
集まってるんやなあ
Have you noticed the atmosphere's
different now, Natsuki-kun?
雰囲気が前と違うやろ
ナツキくんは気づかん？
Now that you mention it, everyone did seem to be in a frenzy. Because of the royal selection?
（スバル）
そう言われれば―
殺気立ってたような
感じはあったな
王選だからか？
（アナスタシア）
上が動けば 人が動く
人が動けば 物が動く
When those on top move, the people move.
When the people move, things move.
By the way, the value of things
in the capital is fluctuatin' a lot now.
ちなみに 今の王都では―
いろいろと物の価値が
変動してるんやけど―
Some of the most valuable products are iron goods.
特に重宝されるんは 鉄製品
Weapons, like swords and spears, are bein'
gathered from both inside and outside.
剣やら槍(やり)やらの武器が
王都の内外から集められとるよ
Iron and weapons?
鉄と武器って
集めてる奴は まさか―
They're not planning to go to war
with those things, are they?
戦争でもする気で
いるんじゃねえだろうな
It's also possible their objective
isn't to acquire the items,
（アナスタシア）
目的は 物 そのものより―
経済を回すことって
可能性もあるよ
but gettin' the economy rolling.
The way you said that...
（スバル）
今の口ぶりだと―
Is it well known who's gathering all this iron?
鉄を集めてる奴が誰なのか
有名なのか？
It's someone you know well, Natsuki-kun.
ナツキくんも
よう知ってるお人やよ
Duchess Crusch Karsten.
クルシュ･カルステン公爵
It's Crusch?
クルシュが…
Come to think of it, she did have
a constant stream of visitors...
そういえば ひっきりなしに
来客があったが…
I get it.
そうか
That's why that Russell guy was there.
ラッセルって男が
顔を見せてたのも それが理由
Russell Fellow?
ラッセル･フェロー？
大物やねえ
He's quite a big fish.
This has been fairly informative.
まあまあ参考になったかなあ
Thank you, Natsuki-kun!
ありがとうな ナツキくん
After fightin' with Crusch-san last night,
you just left her place, right?
ケンカ別れして
クルシュさんとこ出たんが―
昨日の夜やろ？
I figured it'd be easy to learn
今なら 口も目も表情も―
all sorts of information from your mouth, eyes, and expressions!
いろんなところが
滑らせやすいん違うかなと思たんよ
You set me up from the start?
最初から仕組んでいたのかよ
Does using underhanded methods like that
こんなやり方して満足なのかよ？
make you feel good about yourself?
こんな…
だまし討ちみたいなやり方で
If ya want to convince someone you're righteous,
自分の正しさを
信じてもらいたいなら―
you've gotta show somethin' to merit it.
相応のものを見せなアカンよ
And I see no such thing in you.
そして うちは
ナツキくんにそれを見ない
The only way to change your reputation
is to replace it with another.
評価を変えるには
別の評価で覆す以外にない
The things you've done are what
determine your reputation.
評価を決めるんは
それまでの行い つまり過去や
That is, your past.
And there's no way to change your past,
何をどうしても過去は変わらん
so my opinion of ya isn't gonna change, either.
やから うちの中の
ナツキくんの評価も変わらんまま
The things you've done won't ever go away.
やらかしたことは
絶対に消えてなくならんよ
You don't wanna get any closer to my lady.
お兄さん お嬢に
それ以上近づいたらダメ
I'm super strong, you know.
ミミ 超強いから
Thanks, Mimi.
（アナスタシア）
ありがとう ミミ
But you don't have to do anything.
でも 何(なん)もせんでええよ
There's nothin' Natsuki-kun can do, anyway.
ナツキくんも
何もできひんはずやから
Like master, like servant! You're both absolute scum!
（ナツキ）
お前らは 主従そろって最悪だ！
クソ食らえだ！
To hell with it all!
I guess Julius's efforts went to waste...
（アナスタシア）
ユリウスも報われんなあ
うちのせいでもあるけど
It's partly my fault, though.
I guess not even you would
do something that dumb.
さすがに そこまで
バカはしいひんのやね
I'm relieved.
安心したわ
Mimi, let's go.
ミミ 行くよ
'Kay!
（ミミ）あーい
One last thing.
（アナスタシア）
最後に１個だけ
The key to negotiation is how prepared
you are before ya come to the table.
（アナスタシア）
交渉の秘けつは
交渉のテーブルに着く前に―
どれだけ準備できるかで決まる
Know what the other person wants,
and dangle it in front of 'em.
自分が知ってて
相手が欲しがるもんをぶら下げる
And since all you do is want,
that's where you're lackin'.
欲しい欲しいばっかりの
ナツキくんに足らんのは そこやね
Now, it's about time we left.
ほんなら行こか みんな
Shall we, everyone?
See ya later!
（ミミ）お兄さん またね
Bye-bye!
バイバーイ
Damn it!
クソが！
（レム）
スバルくん どうしたんですか
Subaru-kun, what's wrong?
Did something happ—
何かあった…
（スバル）何でもない
Nothing!
Rem, how did it go?
レム 結果はどうだった
I reported the maneuvers by
the Witch Cult to the knights' station.
騎士団詰め所のほうに
魔女教の暗躍を報告してきました
I gave them Roswaal-sama's name, but...
ロズワール様のお名前を
出したのですけど…
Not the response we wanted?
（スバル）
いい返事はもらえなかったか
It seems the knights have received
several such reports already.
（レム）
似たような報告が 騎士団に
いくつも上がっているみたいです
Since the Cult's background is unclear,
魔女教は 背景が
不鮮明ですから―
they said they receive countless
unverifiable, anonymous tips.
確かめようのない密告が
あとを絶たないらしくて
If that's how the real cultists stay hidden,
それで本物が
隠れちまってるってんなら―
it's no laughing matter.
笑えねえ
If we can't scrape a military force together...
戦力をかき集めるのが
不可能だっていうなら―
What shall we do?
（レム）どうしますか
We'll go back to the mansion...
（スバル）屋敷に帰るんだ
Go back and take Emilia and Ram away from there.
戻って エミリアやラムを連れ出す
To the capital or to Roswaal... Anywhere is fine.
王都でも ロズワールが
出かけてる先でもいい
The point being they're in danger right now!
とにかく あの場所は危険なんだ
There's no time.
時間がない すぐにでも出よう
We should leave now.
At this pace, we should reach the mansion by morning.
（スバル）
今のペースなら
朝には屋敷に着ける
That'll give us plenty of time to take Emilia
and the others and run from the Witch Cult.
そうすれば
エミリアたちを連れ出し―
魔女教から逃げる時間は
十分にある
The question is how to transport them.
問題は どうやって運ぶかだ
Isn't that...
あいつは…
From here to the Mathers domain?
（オットー･スーウェン）
これから メイザース領まで？
Yeah.
It's already late. Isn't it too dangerous?
（オットー）
もう夜ですし 危険では？
We were planning to camp here tonight.
僕たちは 今夜ここで
野営するつもりなので―
Would you care to join us?
よければ ご一緒されませんか？
You say that, Otto...
（行商人）
そんなこと言って オットー
But I bet you just wanna get rid of some
お前 時期外して
在庫にした油を―
of the oil in storage that you
bought out of season, right?
少しでも減らしたいだけ
なんじゃねえか？
That's not my intention at all!
そんなつもりじゃありませんよ
Though, it isn't as if I weren't
hoping you could use a little oil.
まあ　少しでも油を
ご利用頂ければ…
という欲が
ない訳ではありませんが
What's this about oil?
油がどうかされたんですか？
Oh, I just made a bit of a mistake.
（オットー）
いえ ちょっとヘマを
やらかしてしまいまして―
And now, I have a lot of oil
that isn't worth much right now.
今の時期 売りものとして
価値が微妙な油を―
大量に抱えているんです
Even if we go to the capital,
I don't know if I can sell it all off...
王都に行っても この油を
全部さばけるかは分かりません
And if I can't, I'm ruined!
そしたら 僕は破産です！
Ruined...
破産です…
Otto, I need to talk—
オットー 話… いや 商談がある
I mean, ask for your help.
I'll buy all the oil in your carriage.
お前の竜車に積んでる油
全部 買い取ってやる
So in return, lend us transport.
代わりに 足を貸してくれ
All of the merchants and carriages here...
ここにいる商人と竜車―
Anyone who'll sell transportation
for money, sell it to me!
足を金で売ってくれる奴は
全員 俺に買われてくれ
We're transporting people!
運ぶのは人だ
People!? We don't want any
part in human trafficking!
人？ 人身売買は勘弁ですよ
I'm not running that kind of side business...
そんなサイドビジネスはしてねえよ
There's a village near the Mathers mansion.
メイザース領の
屋敷近くに村がある
I want you to take its residents somewhere else!
そこの村民たちを乗っけて
移動させたいんだ
We will, of course, thank you properly.
お礼はきちんとさせて頂きます
If we ride through the night,
（オットー）
夜半の間も走り続けて―
we should enter the Mathers domain by morning.
メイザース領へ入るのは
朝方になるでしょうかね
Sorry we can't take breaks.
休憩なしで悪いな
No problem!
（オットー）あっ いえいえ―
Getting rid of my excess stock
and even earning transport fees...
在庫処分ができるうえに 運賃も
はずんでもらえるとなれば―
I feel invincible!
僕は無敵です
Subaru-kun, I'm sorry.
（レム）
スバルくん ごめんなさい
I would like to check the map
to confirm the remaining distance.
残りの距離を確かめたくて
地図を確認したいんです
Map?
地図？
It is in your bag.
スバルくんの荷物の中に
入っているんです
Oh, this?
（スバル）これか
It's too dark to see anything, though...
って… この暗さじゃ
何も見えないな
Ah, I know.
そうだ
Subaru-kun, what is that?
スバルくん それって？
A bit of lost technology.
失われたロストテクノロジー
I mean, it's future technology called a cell phone.
いや 未来テクノロジーの
携帯電話だ
I guess it's a good thing it has
some battery left, if only a little.
かろうじて充電が生きてたみたいで
助かったっていうべきか
Here, look.
これ見てみ
Natsuki-san, what is that?
ナツキさん 何ですか？ それ
Never seen a crystalight like that before.
見たことない結晶灯だな
It's a secret tool the margrave gave me.
辺境伯に持たされてる
秘密の道具なんだよ
Sorry, but you should probably forget you saw it.
悪いけど 見たことは
忘れたほうがいいぞ
Whoa, why does that sound like dark dealings
that reek of nothing but money?
うわ… 何ですか その
お金のにおいしかしない裏事情は
Just a bit farther,
もう少し走った先に―
and we should see Flügel's Tree.
フリューゲルの大樹が
見えてくるはずです
If we head northeast from there,
the Mathers domain isn't far.
そこから北東に向かえば
もうすぐメイザース領ですよ
Flügel's Tree?
（スバル）
フリューゲルの大樹？
A huge tree that stands so tall in the Lifaus
Highway, it seems to pierce the clouds.
（オットー）
リーファウス街道の
真ん中にそびえる―
雲を突くようなでっかい木です
（行商人）
なんでも 数百年前―
Legend has it that, centuries ago,
a wise man named Flügel planted it.
フリューゲルって賢者が
植えたって 伝承が残ってる
I see...
なるほど
こらすげえとしか言えねえよ
I can call that nothing short of amazing.
Where'd the guy in the bandana go?
バンダナのおっさん どこ行った？
He didn't get distracted by the tree
and run off course, did he?
まさか 大樹に見とれて
はぐれたんじゃねえだろうな
What's wrong, Natsuki-san?
どうしました？ ナツキさん
Where'd that buddy of yours go?
お前らの仲間 どこ行った？
The older guy in the bandana,
riding on the other side of us?
さっきまで こっち側を走ってた
バンダナの渋いダンナは
何を言ってるんですか？
What are you talking about?
No one was riding on
the opposite side from me.
僕の反対側なんて
誰も走っていませんでしたよ
Huh?
The  Greedof a  Pig